welcome to meditating with John Breaux
Vicki I'm a cognitive psychologist a
cognitive scientist at the University of
Toronto I academically teach and
scientifically study mindfulness and
related topics like Insight flow
mystical experience transformative
experience higher states of
consciousness cultivation of wisdom and
the aspiration to the Whiteman I've been
practicing the pasta meditation meta
contemplation Tai Chi Chuan and Qigong
for over 29 years and teaching and
professionally for close to 20 years
welcome if you're joining us for the
first time this is a progressive course
and the introductory course is complete
we're now moving into advanced
techniques that are taught every
alternative Monday if you wish to catch
up please go to the notes in this video
and you will find links to the previous
lessons and you can catch up on your own
pace of course welcome to stay if you
wish Monday through Friday we meet at
9:30 a.m. Eastern Time
every alternative Monday is a Dharma day
every day we sit and at the end of every
day there is also a Q&A please keep your
q and a's at the end of the sits two
questions concerning the ecology of
practices this course that I'm teaching
if you have more encompassing questions
or philosophical or existential or
ethical nature please come to my live
streamed Q&A that's every third Friday
of the month that'll be the 19th of June
I believe this month at 3:00 p.m.
Eastern Time
so today is a sick day and so I think
what we should need to do is get
yourself ready oh if you could I always
ask you to do this because it's helpful
to me if you could please remember to
like this video stream that will raise
its visibility in the YouTube algorithm
and help me reach more people
I'm not deriving any income whatsoever
from this and my sole intent is to try
and help people as much as I possibly
can
I think that's everything we need to do
so as I said please set your phones on
Do Not Disturb
get your posture ready we will begin
together when I say baguette begin
Oh
[Music]
perhaps by resetting five promises to
all right
we have time for a question or two
perhaps so these throw your clan I hope
I didn't miss pronounce your name thank
you for attending
I start with my posture straighten after
a few minutes I'd tend to see the
morlocks on the base of my spine is that
okay so if I'm trying to make sure I get
this okay the idea is sort of like this
and then you relax down a bit
well you shouldn't be sort of a rep like
this and holding yourself up you should
actually be sort of sunk down and when I
do that I feel my sits bone touching
myself food my pillow and that allows my
shoulders down open loves my stomach
open so I think if I'm understanding it
correctly that's actually what you want
you want that sense not of holding
yourself up but of actually sinking down
you're a rat but you're sunk and open
and you should be making that very
definite contact with the base of your
spine with your pillow or your chair of
you're sitting on chef Phillip Renault
welcome Phillip asks since music is a
lot like poetry could something like
lick Co Divina be applied to listening
to music or transformation that's a
great question I don't know I've never
tried that one of the advantages of Lexi
o is it acts as a bridge between
propositional and not propositional
cognition between for more abstract and
more embodied cognition music was
already much more sort of non
propositional and embodied and playing
with salience landscaping and relevance
realization so I suppose what I would
say therefore and please remember what I
said I'm ignorant of specifically trying
to apply the practice to Lexia so I'm
speculating here but given some of the
goals of Luxio I would not recommend
replacing Alexio with text or poetry
with music because you're losing some of
what you're gaining when the Alexio is
with text the sense of logos as the
bridge between the proposition or the
non propositional but I see no reason
why you couldn't apply something why
collects you in addition to music and
I'd be interested in knowing what
happens when you do so so one more
question
I think for today and then we'll start
wrapping it up please remember that on
Tuesdays and Thursdays we have to be
done no later than 10 o'clock
harima can one turn to arrive Jim random
page in lectio divina if the material
has been read before at one time yes so
I tried both strategies because I try to
thwart the fact that implicitly she nuri
can predict huge patterns outside of our
awareness so Monday through Friday
I read sequentially and that's
recommended because it's recommended
especially when yours to you that you
stick with the text right you stick with
the text even when you find it perhaps a
bit boring but then I switch on Saturday
and Sunday to doing what karema
recommends where I randomly I read from
this different set of text right now I'm
reading ontology approach it by Rumi and
for my prose I'm reading
Dionysius the Areopagite and they're
what I do is I pick them up and I do the
random selection to again just
constantly keep the level of challenge
try to keep me in the zone of proximal
development
so I actually move between those two
strategies I don't know that's good
necessarily if you're just picking it up
for the first time you might want to
just continue this essential for a while
I'm not sure about this because I
haven't had enough interaction with
novices trying this but it sounds like
creamy you are having success
I recommend alternating between the two
as I do because again we're in our
ecology of practices notice what we're
doing we're always trying to find
complementary sets of strengths and
weaknesses trade off relationships and
get everything into tonus everything
into this creative tension with
everything else so thank you very much
for joining I really appreciate this
Sangha I want everyone to know that
knowing that I can make a difference
matters to me knowing that I can help
others matters to me and also you are
all helping me you are all helping me
Deeping deepen my practice there is no
better way to learn than to teach if
you're doing really good teaching really
good teaching is not just giving
information it is to share
transformation together I want to thank
my techno mage and dear friend Omar was
always there always and Jason as always
like today just how to get up and close
the door how do door because noise he's
always there handling things on the fly
and the environment thank you so much
please subscribe to this channel to be
notified of the next video we'll also
find links to the lecture series awaking
from the meaning crisis and the
discussion the Lobos to Sirius voices
with rebecky
where all of these topics and more and
the more encompassing framework are
explored in depth and developed
developed in concert with other people
invite others who might benefit to
please join this series as I said I'm
trying to help as many people as I can
pleasure of that Brett is here he is
here and there are links in the
description to the discord server where
you can go people have been here on the
discord server server with the signing
of sitting and then you can go there and
you can join that group and talk about
the practice perhaps do Alexio de vino'
together and then there's just a broader
community in which just it's a beautiful
community I think a new culture is
emerging there a culture that is
oriented towards meaning and wisdom and
waking up and transformation I every
alternative Monday at 6:00
I am 6:00 on
time I'm on that discord server doing a
general QA we're doing this practice
every weekday morning 9:30 Eastern Time
please remember continuity of practice
more important than quantity there is no
enemy worse than your own mind and body
there is no friend no allied root no
true companion on the way better than
your own mind and body be lamps unto
yourself take care everyone and I'll see
you tomorrow